JOSÉ NUNES

FRONTEND WEB DEVELOPER

(+351) 934 243 406

jn@josenunes.xyz

www.linkedin.com/in/josé-nunes-rr

Aveiro, Portugal

MOTIVATION LETTER - Frontend developer

TO WHOM IT MAY CONCERN,

My name is José Nunes, I'm 34 years old, and I am a Frontend developer from Portugal, currently working at adidas (www.adidas-group.com). I have been a software developer for 6 years. Although I started my IT career as a Python developer, I've been working as a frontend web developer for the past 3 years. My initial tech stack was focused on vanilla JavaScript and jQuery. Nowadays, I work mainly with modern frontend web technologies in the React ecosystem. In fact, I've been working as React developer for more than two years now. Some of the technologies I use daily in my work are:

- React
- Redux for state management
- Webpack as the bundler
- Babel to transpile both JSX and ES6
- Storybook to document React components
- npm as the package manager
- Jest/Enzyme for unit-testing
- ESlint and StyleLint for code linting
- Prettier for code formatting
- CSS modules and PostCSS (I've also worked with Styled-Components)
- redux-thunk and axios for AJAX
- react-intl-redux for i18n
- · react-router to handle routing
- Git for version control
- and the list goes on.

Right now, I'm looking to embrace a new professional challenge. I'm available to provide further information, and also to prove my skills in technical evaluations.

Best regards, José Nunes

JOSÉ NUNES

FRONTEND WEB DEVELOPER

(+351) 934 243 406

jn@josenunes.xyz

www.linkedin.com/in/josé-nunes-rr

Aveiro, Portugal

RECENT WORK EXPERIENCES

adidas AG

adidas AG (www.adidas-group.com) needs no introduction. It is the largest sportswear manufacturer in Europe, and the second largest in the world. With its headquarters in Herzogenaurach, Germany, employs nearly 57,000 people around the world.

At adidas, I worked as a frontend web developer, integrated on a multidisciplinary Scrum team, in the development of a B2B React/Redux web app called "Click" ("Click" is a self-service order intake platform for small and medium wholesale customers).

FRONTEND WEB DEVELOPER (REACT/REDUX)

Mar 2018 - Dec 2018

doDOC CORP.

doDOC (www.dodoc.com) is software development company with headquarters in Boston (USA) and Coimbra (Portugal). doDOC product is a single platform solution for secure collaboration when working with complex and regulated documents.

At doDOC, my job was to migrate the front-end (written in vanilla JavaScript and jQuery), as well as new product features, into a React/Redux SPA.

FRONTEND WEB DEVELOPER (REACT/REDUX)

Oct 2016 - Feb 2018

Soundzipper

Soundzipper is a Singapore based acoustics consultancy company. I've worked (part-time) with Soundzipper as a front-end developer.

My primary role inside the company was the development and maintenance of the website (www.soundzipper.com).

FRONTEND WEB DEVELOPER

Sep 2015 - Sep 2017

OOF, Lda

OOF (www.oof.pt) is a commercial art and graphic design company from Guimarães, Portugal.

I worked with OOF to implement a website for the Social Studies department of the University of Coimbra, Portugal (www.exchange.ces.uc.pt). My job was to convert static mockups into a jQuery site with a Wordpress back-end.

FRONTEND WEB DEVELOPER

May 2016 - Jun 2016

EDUCATION

SKILLS

React

Git

PhD (ENGINEERING)

Jan 2007 - Mar 2010

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE DEGREE

Feb 2003 - Sep 2006

Redux

JS (ES6)

jQuery

HTML

CSS

Storybook
Webpack
Yarn/npm
Node
Wordpress
PHP

Wordpress
PHP
Unit-testing